<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2010-05-20T02:00:00+02:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; margin: 20px 20px 20px 0px; display: inline; border-top: 0px; border-right: 0px" title="RD Logo PNG" border="0" alt="RD Logo PNG" align="left" src="http://blog.goeran.no/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/ImjoiningtheMicrosoftRegionalDirectorpro_BDFE/RD%20Logo%20PNG_3.png" width="206" height="59" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;During the last month I’ve been in dialog with &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-schuler/10/619/477" target="_blank"&gt;Kevin Schuler&lt;/a&gt; regarding joining the Microsoft Regional Director program. Yesterday everything fell into place, and I can now announce that I’m onboard the program. I’m up for a two year period; 2009 and 2010. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;It’s an honor for me to join the program. There are about 120-130 Regional Directors worldwide. In Norway we are now 4 Regional Directors – my friends &lt;a href="http://jonas.follesoe.no" target="_blank"&gt;Jonas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.sondreb.com" target="_blank"&gt;Sondre&lt;/a&gt;, Trond Brande and me.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://jonas.follesoe.no/ItsOfficialImNowAMicrosoftRegionalDirector.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Like Jonas said&lt;/a&gt; when he joined; it feels strange to become a member of such a highly qualified and experienced group of people. Many people in this group are well known technical speakers and book authors. I’m sure I’ll grow with the new responsibilities, and that I’m able to contribute to the group. I’ll continue to work hard on evangelizing Microsoft technologies and software development best practices to the community. This is definitely a motivational boost for me!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I would like to say thank you to Microsoft Norway and &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/grothaug" target="_blank"&gt;Rune Grothaug&lt;/a&gt; for making this happen.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;What is a Microsoft Regional Director?&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;“The Microsoft Regional Director (RD) program is a community of independent developers, architects, trainers, and other professionals who form a vital link between Microsoft and the developer community. These technical experts provide insight and informed perspectives about Microsoft software development tools and technologies. Regional Directors are not Microsoft employees, nor are they monetarily-compensated by Microsoft. They are recognized by Microsoft for their technical expertise. Many Regional Directors are also Microsoft MVPs.” – &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Regional_Director" target="_blank"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2010-05-20T13:30:47.7276496+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2010-05-20T13:35:32.2969762+02:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>95cce4b3-e60c-4e5a-8bb5-fdcdfd03da4a</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>I&amp;rsquo;m joining the Microsoft Regional Director program</Title>
      <Categories>Community;Microsoft RD</Categories>
      <Author>admin</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.goeran.no/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/CredsfromMicrosoftformycommunitycontribu_A018/MVP_5F00_FullColor_5F00_ForScreen_2.png"&gt;&lt;img style="border-right-width: 0px; margin: 0px 8px 4px 0px; display: inline; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; border-left-width: 0px" title="MVP_5F00_FullColor_5F00_ForScreen" border="0" alt="MVP_5F00_FullColor_5F00_ForScreen" align="left" src="http://blog.goeran.no/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/CredsfromMicrosoftformycommunitycontribu_A018/MVP_5F00_FullColor_5F00_ForScreen_thumb.png" width="153" height="240" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; About a month ago I got some really good news. Microsoft had awarded me with the &lt;a href="http://mvp.support.microsoft.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Most Valuable Professional&lt;/a&gt; (MVP) title. My title was in the &lt;a href="https://mvp.support.microsoft.com/communities/mvp.aspx?product=1&amp;amp;competency=Client+App+Dev" target="_blank"&gt;Client App Dev&lt;/a&gt; category. And it’s a perfect match for me, since I’m into several kinds of technologies in the user interface area; ASP.NET MVC, Silverlight and WPF. I got the award for the &lt;a href="http://blog.goeran.no/CategoryView,category,Presentation.aspx"&gt;community work I’ve done&lt;/a&gt; during the last couple of years. This work has consisted of technical presentations at user groups, and commercial conferences like the Microsoft MSDN Live road show. I’m also active in the local .NET user group in Trondheim, where I help out organizing and executing the monthly meetings.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I’m humbled to be recognized and awarded with this title. I have to say thanks to the former Community Manager at Microsoft; &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/grothaug" target="_blank"&gt;Rune Grothaug&lt;/a&gt;. Without the help and support from him, I wouldn’t have gotten the award. While he was working as a Community Manager we did many things together, for instance &lt;a href="http://blog.goeran.no/CategoryView,category,MSDN%2BLive.aspx"&gt;MSDN Live&lt;/a&gt;. He organized, and I contributed with technical presentations. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In the future I plan to keep on doing what I’m already doing, but I will make some adjustments. I’ll try to contribute more to the global community through online forums and my blog. This will both give me more visibility and reach. I’ll continue to focus on Silverlight and WPF. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Since I’ve become an MVP, I’ll hopefully be invited to Redmond for the next MVP Summit. I’m looking forward to this!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I’m proud to follow in the footsteps of other Norwegian Microsoft MVP’s;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ingebrigtsen.info/" target="_blank"&gt;Einar Ingebrigtsen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://jonas.follesoe.no" target="_blank"&gt;Jonas Follesø&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.joaroyen.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Joar Øyen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.joaroyen.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Pål Fossmo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.larswilhelmsen.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Lars Wilhelmsen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sondreb.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Sondre Bjellås&lt;/a&gt; – not an MVP, but a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Regional_Director" target="_blank"&gt;Regional Director&lt;/a&gt;. Had to mention him, because he is a great contributor to the Norwegian developer community&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;What is an MVP?&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;“The Microsoft Most Valuable Professional (MVP) is an award presented by Microsoft for the employees or individuals or consultants working outside Microsoft. Microsoft MVPs are exceptional technical community leaders from around the world who have been awarded for voluntarily providing technical expertise towards technical communities supporting Microsoft products or technologies. An MVP is awarded for contributions over the past year.” – &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Most_Valuable_Professional" target="_blank"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;  &lt;h3&gt;What does it take to become an MVP?&lt;/h3&gt;  &lt;blockquote&gt;   &lt;p&gt;“The MVP Award recognizes exceptional technical community leaders from around the world who voluntarily share their deep, real-world knowledge about Microsoft technologies with others. &lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;Potential MVPs are nominated by other technical community members, current and former MVPs, and Microsoft personnel who have noted their leadership and their willingness and ability to help others make the most of their Microsoft technology. &lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;To receive the Microsoft MVP Award, MVP nominees undergo a rigorous review process. A panel that includes members of the MVP team and Microsoft product groups evaluates each nominee's technical expertise and voluntary community contributions for the past 12 months. The panel considers the quality, quantity, and level of impact of the MVP nominee's contributions. Active MVPs receive the same level of scrutiny as other new candidates each year. &lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;MVPs are independent of Microsoft, with separate opinions and perspectives, and are able to represent the views of the community members with whom they engage every day. &lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;Click here if you would like to nominate an outstanding community leader, or an exceptional contributor to the technical community, for consideration as an MVP.” - &lt;a href="http://mvp.support.microsoft.com/gp/mvpbecoming" target="_blank"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2010-05-20T11:35:36.3019507+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2010-05-20T11:57:07.0879081+02:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>e0a4c436-34ae-4d78-ae4a-62d336f7f95b</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Creds from Microsoft for my community contributions!</Title>
      <Categories>Community;mvp</Categories>
      <Author>admin</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>